
final Map<String, List<Map<String, dynamic>>> unit1QuizData = {
  'Why python': [
    {
      'question': 'Who developed Python and in which year?',
      'answers': ['James Gosling, 1995', 'Guido van Rossum, 1990', 'Bjarne Stroustrup, 1985', 'Dennis Ritchie, 1972'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Guido van Rossum, 1990',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following is NOT an advantage of Python?',
      'answers': ['Readability of code', 'Platform independence', 'Limited library support', 'Supports third-party software like NumPy'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Limited library support',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Python is primarily what type of programming language?',
      'answers': ['Procedural', 'Object-Oriented', 'Assembly', 'Functional'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Object-Oriented',
    },
  ],
  'Python comments': [
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following is a correct Python comment?',
      'answers': ['// This is comment', '# This is comment', '-- This is comment', '/* This is comment*/'],
      'correctAnswer': '# This is comment',
    },
  ],
  'Variables': [
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following is a valid Python variable name?',
      'answers': ['2value', 'name@1', '_student_name', 'for'],
      'correctAnswer': '_student_name',
    },
  ],
  'Keywords': [
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following is a Python keyword?',
      'answers': ['print', 'Name', 'False', 'value'],
      'correctAnswer': 'False',
    },
  ],
  'Data type': [
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following represents a valid Python complex number?',
      'answers': ['5.6.2', '7+j2', '3+5j', '3+5i'],
      'correctAnswer': '3+5j',
    },
    {
      'question': 'What is the data type of the value 2.75 in Python?',
      'answers': ['int', 'float', 'complex', 'bool'],
      'correctAnswer': 'float',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following is a Boolean value in Python?',
      'answers': ['"True"', 'true', '1', 'True'],
      'correctAnswer': 'True',
    },
  ],
  'Operators': [
    {
      'question': 'Which operator is used for exponentiation in Python?',
      'answers': ['*', '**', '^', '%'],
      'correctAnswer': '**',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following is a logical operator in Python?',
      'answers': ['&', '<<', 'and', '=='],
      'correctAnswer': 'and',
    },
    {
      'question': 'What does the bitwise operator >> do?',
      'answers': ['Right shift bits', 'Left shift bits', 'Bitwise OR', 'Bitwise XOR'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Right shift bits',
    },
  ],
  'Classes and objects': [
    {
      'question': 'Which keyword is used to create a class in Python?',
      'answers': ['object', 'class', 'def', 'create'],
      'correctAnswer': 'class',
    },
    {
      'question': 'What is an object in Python?',
      'answers': ['A built-in function', 'A specific instance of a class with data', 'A comment inside class', 'A type of operator'],
      'correctAnswer': 'A specific instance of a class with data',
    },
  ],
  'Encapsulation': [
    {
      'question': 'In Encapsulation, which prefix is used to make a variable private in Python?',
      'answers': ['_ (singleunderscore)', '#', '__ (doubleunderscore)', '@'],
      'correctAnswer': '__ (doubleunderscore)',
    },
  ],
  'inheritance': [
    {
      'question': 'What is the primary benefit of inheritance in OOP?',
      'answers': ['To hide data from other classes', 'To create multiple forms of a method', 'To allow a class to use properties and methods of another class', 'To group similar objects together'],
      'correctAnswer': 'To allow a class to use properties and methods of another class',
    },
  ],
};
